Ahmet OZKESEK

Ground Floor Flat 17 Stonor Road West Kensington W14 8RZ LONDON

M: 0772 922 3112

E: <u>aozkesek@gmail.com</u>

Summary

I am 25+ years experienced Software Developer/Programmer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering. I developed, planned and designed various software for Contact Centre, ATM Management, Document Management and Workflow Management. I worked 16 years in Banking and Financial sector in Istanbul-Turkey. Now, I am seeking a Software Developer role in London where I can continue to improve myself in English.

Experience

Oct 2016 – date Istanbul - London Freelancer	
--	--

- Chose voluntarily to be unemployed and focused myself
- Self studying Java EE
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-809 OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II (81%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-ocp.pdf
- Self studied, passed exam 1Z0-808 OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I (94%) https://github.com/aozkesek/cv/blob/master/eCertificate-oca.pdf
- Designing and developing an Android Video Chat Application https://github.com/aozkesek/p2p-cast
- Designed and developed a Hospital Management Software with Biometric Verification for ZieZix360 from Nigeria. It was a Proof of Concept application that contains a Fingerprint and a Camera reader service module, multiple web service modules, and a web UI module. https://github.com/aozkesek/ziezix360-hm https://ziezix360.com/about-us/
- Developed a group of PoC applications for an e-commerce web site and it's test automations https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce

https://github.com/aozkesek/alev-e-commerce https://github.com/aozkesek/selenium-json-suite-runner

Jul 2014 - Aug 2016	NETAS, Istanbul	Consultant
---------------------	-----------------	------------

- Designed and wrote Technical Design Document to submit a proposal for companies used Cisco Unified Communication and IP Desktop Phones.
- Created a prototype of IP Phone Service to join AVAYA Developer Connect Program
 https://www.devconnectprogram.com/site/global/program_benefits/overview/index.gsp
 https://downloads.avaya.com/css/P8/documents/101026461
- Developed a web application for managing a group of Cisco IP Phone Services https://github.com/aozkesek/iis-app-manager

 https://github.com/aozkesek/license-manager

_

Trained the junior team members

Nov 2001 - Jan 2014	Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul	Senior Programmer
 	10.10.	1

- Led a Workflow Management Development team for 3 months
- Developed and maintained workflow and document management service
- Developed and maintained automatic teller machine service
- Involved upgrading of contact centre infrastructure and hardware
- Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Developed and maintained on-line and telephone banking service

Skills

- Java 8 SE OCP Oracle Certified Professional https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/73245c76-e69e-4d2f-9513-780e5e98aae8
- C#, C, JavaScript
- · Oracle, MS-SQL, PostgreSQL Relational DB
- Junit, TestNG, Selenium Test Driven Development
- · Gradle, Maven, Git, Docker
- Spring Framework Java EE, Hibernate ORM, JSF & Primefaces, Apache Struts, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, PostSharp
- JTAPI & Cisco, Genesys CTI & IVR

Education

University of Istanbul, 1990 – 1997, Bachelor of Technology in Computer Sciences Engineering (http://bilgisayar.muhendislik.istanbulc.edu.tr)

Qualifications

- OCP Java 8 SE Programmer II, London, (1Z0-809, 81%, 2020-01-30)
- OCA Java 8 SE Programmer I, London, (1Z0-808, 94%, 2019-10-16)
- Genesys, Istanbul, 2010: IP IVR Development Course
- Cisco, Istanbul, 2007: Cisco Unified Communication Manager Course
- Yapi Kredi Bank, Istanbul, 2005: Java Server Pages, MVC Apache Struts Course
- Genesys, San Fransisco, 2001: Genesys Certified Developer
- Netron, Istanbul, 1999: Internet Information Server (IIS), Active Server Page (ASP), Component Object Model (COM) Course